

## **Yanick Senn**

E-Mail info@vanicksenn.com

Website yanicksenn.com

**GitHub** github.com/yanicksenn

**Highlights** Java, Kotlin, C#, SQL, Maven, Docker, Spring,

Typescript, Angular, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

## Summary

Skilled software engineer with 6+ years of working experience and a BSc in Computer Science. A quick learner who can absorb and contribute new ideas and concepts. Always pushing to reduce technical debt and optimizing processes in software development. Experienced in OOP and functional programming as well as TDD, BDD, and property-based testing. Reliable team player with strong oral and written communication skills. Staying in the loop through contributions to open-source and personal projects.

### **Education**

**ZHAW School of Engineering** Zürich BSc in Computer Science 2018 - 2022

**BBB Berufsbildung Baden** Baden Federal VET Diploma (Application developer EFZ) 2012 - 2016Vocational baccalaureate (BMS) 2012 - 2016

## **Experience**

### **Worldline Schweiz AG**

Zürich

Software-Engineer

Feb. 2021 - Now

- Developed and maintained software to handle the processing of card payments.
- Held technical interviews with potential new employees.
- Took ownership in various projects regarding PCI DSS.
- Presented newly developed components and tools in department wide trainings.

Java Kotlin PL/SQL Spring Eclipse-RCP Docker Maven Shell

**Baden-Dättwil** aXenta AG 2016 - Jan. 2021

Software-Engineer (Full Stack)

- · Designed, developed, and maintained a web-interface called PKCockpit for second-pillar pension funds.
- Developed specific rest services for clients of PKCockpit.
- Held department wide trainings for unit, integration, and property-based testing.
- Organized a company internal hackathon to evaluate a suitable web-framework for PKCockpit.

Java | Java EE | TypeScript | Angular | HTML/CSS | PL/SQL | AWT/Swing | Gradle

**Baden-Dättwil** aXenta AG 2012 - 2016

#### Software-Engineer Apprentice

- Resolved software bugs and participated in company internal projects.
- Implemented an iOS application that allows full-text search for Swiss laws.
- Developed a tool to unify and automate screenshots for release manuals. (IPA)

Java PL/SQL EJB2 / EJB3 AWT/Swing Objective-C Batch

## Languages

Java Kotlin C#

SQL / PL/SQL

Shell / Bash / Batch / PowerShell

TypeScript / JavaScript

HTML / CSS

### **Other**

Agile / SCRUM TDD / BDD OOP / Functional Programming Blockchain Development with Solidity Microsoft Office

# **About myself**

## Non programming languages

- German (Mother tongue)
- English

#### **Interests**

- Motorsports (Go-Kart in Swiss National Championship)
- Game-Development
- Gaming
- Drums

## Frameworks & Tools

Maven / Gradle Spring / Spring-Boot Docker / Podman Unity3d Node.js / Angular Jenkins Git / Perforce